♪〜
〜♪
Vash...
（ミリオンズ･ナイヴズ）
ヴァッシュ ヴァッシュ！
Vash!
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
ああ…
Can you stand, Vash?
（ナイヴズ）
立てるか？ ヴァッシュ
（ヴァッシュ）うう…
（ナイヴズ）おっと！
Oops!
なんだよ！
What was that for? It's just
you and me, like two brothers on our own.
僕たちは たった２人きりの
兄弟みたいなものだろう？
This is all your fault!
すべて お前のせいだ！
You killed Rem...
レムも…
みんなも…
...the crew...
...you killed them all!!
お前が殺したんだ！
Yes, and it's very colorful.
It's superb...
ああ とても晴れやかだ
すばらしい
...aside from the fraction who will
be saved because of Rem's meddling.
レムのせいで助かってしまう—
あの中の何％のこと以外はね
Where are you going?
（ヴァッシュ）どこへ行く！
There's no use staying here.
（ナイヴズ）ここにいても
しょうがないだろう
Come on. Or would
you rather stay here...
来いよ
それとも ここで
メソメソ泣き続けるかい？
...and cry your eyes out?
This is a terrible environment,
just as I predicted.
（ナイヴズ）観測してたとおり
すさまじい環境だな
It'll be impossible for
the trash to live here.
これじゃ クズどもが
生きていくことは 不可能だな
It can still work out
if they use the plants.
（ヴァッシュ）
プラントがあれば なんとかなる
Yeah, probably!
（ナイヴズ）そうだろうよ
They'll survive by leeching off
the living blood of our siblings.
僕たちの兄弟の生き血を吸って
やつらは生き長らえるんだ
I can hear the screams of our brethren,
the death cries of our friends!
聞こえるよ 仲間の悲鳴が
友達の断末魔が
Is that why you kill people?!
（ヴァッシュ）
だから人を殺すのか！
That's right.
（ナイヴズ）そうだよ
チョウを守るためにクモを消す
I kill spiders
to save butterflies.
It's simple logic.
単純な理屈さ
Don't forget!
He killed them!
（ヴァッシュ）忘れるな
こいつが殺したんだ
Yes. He killed...
そう こいつが…
... Rem!!
レムを！
（レム･セイブレム）誰も
人の命を奪う権利なんてないわ
No one has the right
to take the life of another.
（ヴァッシュ）うっ
うう…
ん… ああ
あっ
（ナイヴズ）ヴァッシュ！
Hey, Vash!
Let's get going soon.
そろそろ出発しようか
（水を注ぐ音）
（男Ａ）ハア ハア ハア…
ああ ああ ああっ！
（女性の悲鳴）
（男Ｂ）おい！
Hey!
（人々の怒号）
That is the true nature
of the beasts called humans.
あれが
人間という生き物の本質だ
They're selfish, arrogant,
insolent, and imperfect organisms.
利己的で 傲慢(ごうまん)で 不遜(ふそん)なる
不完全な生命体
They make me sick!
まったくもって ヘドが出る
（人々のおびえる声）
What is that?
What did you do?!
（ヴァッシュ）何だ！ 何をした！
何をしたんだ！
Now we have our own wills.
僕らは意志を持った
No longer are we merely
"things" to be used.
使われるだけの存在では
なくなったのさ
What are you saying?!
（ヴァッシュ）君は何を…
（ナイヴズ）
フフフ… 見つけたぞ
I found it.
The damage isn't all
that bad. It'll do.
破損状況は悪くない
いけるな
What are you going to do?
何を考えてるんだ？
I'm just going to fetch
something I left behind.
忘れ物を取りにいくだけさ
It may take me a little while
to find it, but wait here.
捜してくる
少し かかるかもしれないが
待っててくれ
Knives?
ナイヴズ
It's hard to be alone...
I don't want to be alone...
一人はつらい
一人はイヤだよ…
誰か…
Someone...
（物音）
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
Knives!
ナイヴズ！
All done.
できた
Knives!
（ヴァッシュ）ナイヴズ！
おい！ どこ行くつもりだ
Hey, where are you going?
（衝撃音）
（ヴァッシュ）うわっ！
えっ？
A 13% output. I guess
that's as good as it gets.
出力13％　こんなもんだな
W-What is that?!
（ヴァッシュ）
な… 何だ？ それは
Our brethren.
This one's yours.
僕らの兄弟さ
これは お前の分だ
We are going to use these guns
to wipe mankind off the planet.
この銃を使って
二人で人類をなぎ払うんだ
I...
I can't possibly do that!
そ… そんなことができるか！
Do it.
やるんだよ
Never!
ダメだ！
Then why did you follow me?
だったら なぜ僕についてきた
Because you're hopeless
on your own, right?
一人では
何もできないからだろう？
All right, just watch.
じゃあ 見てればいいさ
だ… ダメだ！
Don't!!
（２人の争う声）
Are you still worried about
that nonsense after 15 years?
15年もたったというのに
まだ気にしているのか？
The self-contradicting nonsense
of a stupid woman.
大いなる矛盾を抱えた
あの女のざれ言を
（ヴァッシュ）ええい…
これ以上 人は殺させない！
I won't let you kill
any more!
Hey, I think you got
the wrong idea somewhere.
（ナイヴズ）おいおい
何を勘違いしてるんだよ
You're supposed to aim
that at them, not me.
向ける相手が違うだろ
They're all alive!
（ヴァッシュ）みんな生きてる
Alive!!
生きてるんだ！
I promised Rem...
レムと約束したんだ
...that we would
make this land into...
僕たちは ここで…
That's right! You and I
are going to make this land into...
（ナイヴズ）
そう！ ここで作るんだ
...our private...
僕と君の… エデンを
...Eden.
It's wrong...
（ヴァッシュ）いけない
いけない
It's wrong!
WRONG!
いけないんだ！
（銃声）
（ナイヴズ）ああ…
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
足が… 僕の足が 痛い
My leg!
My leg...
...hurts.
What is this pain?
この痛さは何だ
撃ったのか？
Did you shoot me?
僕を撃ったのか？
Did you really shoot me?!
この僕を撃ったというのか！
あっ ああーっ！
ああーっ！
Wait...
（ナイヴズ）待て… ヴァッシュ
Vash!!
うっ うう…
（ヴァッシュ）ハア ハア ハア…
あっ
Rem...
レ… レム
Where?
ここは…
（キーをたたく音）
あっ！
（ヴァッシュ）
この人は… レムの血縁
This man is related to Rem!
He's still alive!
まだ生きていたのか
I have to tell him about Rem!
レムのことを伝えるんだ
あっ！
Hey, Vash!
（ナイヴズ）よう！ ヴァッシュ
（ヴァッシュ）ああ… ああ…
Now everything joining
you and Rem is gone.
（ナイヴズ）これで
君とレムをつなぐものは—
すべてなくなったね
Is that...
Is that your excuse?!
それが… それが理由か！
What have you learned
these past 100 years?
（ナイヴズ）君は この100年
何を学んできた？
The scars carved into you
will never regenerate.
その体に刻み込まれた傷は
再利用もできない
You are living proof
of the folly of human trash.
ゴミどもの愚かな行為
そのものだよ
You're wrong.
They're all alive.
お前は間違ってる
みんな生きてる… 生きてるんだ！
Alive!
Why grow up if you only
grow more sentimental?
（ナイヴズ）
おセンチなところだけ成長しても
しょうがないだろうが
...you good-for-nothing
weepy-faced kid!
このメソメソ泣いているだけの
ガキが！
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）うわあっ！
ぐああ… くっ
（指を鳴らす音）
こ… この光は
W-What's this light?
It's something
you and I can do.
（ナイヴズ）
これが 僕と君の能力だ
Now, let's dispose
of all the trash.
さあ なぎ払おう
すべてのゴミを！
わっ うわあー！
ああっ あーっ くっ！
うわあーっ
あっ あっ ああーっ！
Are you going
to shoot me again?
（ナイヴズ）また 僕を狙うのか？
（ヴァッシュ）ああーっ！
Are you really going
to shoot me again...
また僕を狙うというのか
ヴァッシュ！
...Vash?!!!
（衝撃音）
Make Vash suffer...
（ナイヴズ）
ヴァッシュに苦しみを
Make Vash suffer eternally.
絶え間ない苦しみを与えるのだ
I know, my master.
（レガート･ブルーサマーズ）
分かっております
この腕の男に苦しみを
The man belonging to
this arm will suffer.
Go up with this town,
Vash the Stampede!!
（モネヴ･ザ･ゲイル）
この町ごと消えちまいな！
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
（モネヴ）うわっ！
あっ ああ…
You're naive.
If I was so inclined...
（ドミニク･ザ･サイクロプス）
甘いわね
今 私がもし その気だったら—
...I could have
killed you three times.
あなた３回は死んでるわよ
お前がやったのか！
Did you kill them?!
（Ｅ･Ｇ･マイン）うるさいねえ
Damn, you're noisy...
What if I did, chicken shit?
それが どうだってんだよ
チキン野郎
（刺す音）
（マイン）うっ！
ああ…
Come on.
（ヴァッシュ）来な
I am in your debt.
（雷泥(らいでい)･ザ･ブレード）
かたじけない　いざ！
Get ready!
Run!!!
（ヴァッシュ）逃げろ！
What is that?!
何なのだ？
それは いったい何なのだー？
What the hell is that?!
（衝撃音）
（ブラド）うっ うう…
Brad...
（ヴァッシュ）ブラド！ ブラド！
BRAD!!!
（銃声）
Why did you shoot him?!
なぜ 撃った！
What alternative do I have?
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
ほかに 方法がないやろが
We live too differently!
生き方が違いすぎる
And he's not alone.
それに もう一人
I failed to save another life.
（ヴァッシュ）
また助けられなかったよ
Just be more careful
the next time.
（ウルフウッド）
今度は ちゃんとやり
（爆発音）
Shoot me
of your own free will.
（レガート）僕を撃つんだ
自分の意志で
（メリル･ストライフと
ミリィ･トンプソンの悲鳴）
（銃声）
フフフフフ… アハハハッ
Did you have fun
living as a human?
楽しかったかい？
人間として生きて
Yeah!
It was the greatest!
ああ 最高だったとも
（銃声）
（ナイヴズ）うん？
（発砲音）
ハア ハア…
フッ
（爆発音と銃声）
あっ！
（銃声）
ハア ハア ハア…
（ヴァッシュ）
（ナイヴズ）
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
（銃声）
うわあっ！ クッ
うあっ くっ
（ナイヴズ）フッ
（ヴァッシュ）ああっ
フフン…
ああ…
（衝撃音）
He cancelled me out!
（ナイヴズ）打ち消した
I didn't make them
to be used like that!
そういう使い方をするために
作ったわけじゃない
They're practically
meaningless otherwise.
（ヴァッシュ）
こういう使い方ぐらいしか
意味のないものだ
（ナイヴズ）
もう… ダメなんだな
I guess I can't talk
sense into you, huh?
Yeah, I've already
made my decision.
（ヴァッシュ）選んだからな
You are not a human being,
you're a plant.
（ナイヴズ）
君は人間じゃない　プラントだ
I know that.
（ヴァッシュ）分かってるさ
You're a superior breed.
（ナイヴズ）優良種だ
Oh, really?
（ヴァッシュ）それはどうかな？
（空撃ちする音）
ヘヘッ
（ナイヴズ）お前は間違ってる！
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）うわっ！
You are wrong!
（ナイヴズ）ううう… くっ
（ヴァッシュ）
間違いは二度と犯さない
（ヴァッシュ）くうっ くっ
ハア ハア…
ハア ハア ハア…
（衝撃音）
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
（銃声）
I will not repeat
my mistakes!
（ヴァッシュ）ああ…
ハア… うっ
（空撃ちする音）
（蹴り上げる音）
（ヴァッシュ）ぐわっ
What are you doing,
you idiot?!
ううっ… くっ
うああ… くっ
（ウルフウッド）
何やっとんねん このドアホ！
It's right next to you!
Use it, dammit!!!
すぐそばにあるねん
使わんかい！
あっ…
（発砲音）
うわあっ！
（銃声）
（ナイヴズ）うわっ！ ああ…
うう… うわああーっ
（銃声）
ハア ハア ハア…
（ナイヴズ）うう…
ああ…
ハア ハア…
I...
俺は…
I will...
...survive!
生き抜く
（地響き）
（人々の歓声）
（男性）水が出た！
（黒猫の鳴き声）
Ma'am, water!!!
（ミリィ）先輩！ 水です！
We struck water!!
水が出ました
（メリル）ええ
Yeah!
エヘヘヘ… エヘッ
Mr. Vash will
come back, won't he?
（ミリィ）ヴァッシュさん
戻ってきますよね？
You're darned right he will!
（メリル）当たり前ですわ
He wouldn't keep
a good woman like me waiting!
こんないい女が
待ってるんですもの
Rem...
（ヴァッシュ）
レム　僕は君を信じ続ける
... I will continue
to believe in you!
And from now on, I will
search for my own words.
そして これからは
自分の言葉を探してみるよ
♪〜
〜♪